<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cv on Amelia E. Barber </title>
    <link>/tags/cv/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cv on Amelia E. Barber </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/cv/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/top/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/top/about/</guid>
      <description>About Me I am currently a postdoc at the Leibniz Institute of Natural Product Research and Infection Biology - Hans Knöll Institute in Jena, Germany and the Institute for Hygiene and Microbiology at the University of Würzburg studying fungal biology and comparitive genomics of Aspergillus and Candida spp, with a special focus on antifungal resistance.
Prior to that, I was a PhD student at the University of Utah in the group of Matthew Mulvey studying how the vast genetic diversity seen in Escherichia coli strains translates to differences in disease progression and host response during sepsis using a novel zebrafish model of disease we developed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/2019/07/20/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/07/20/about-me/</guid>
      <description>I am currently a postdoc at the Leibniz Institute of Natural Product Research and Infection Biology - Hans Knöll Institute in Jena, Germany and the Institute for Hygiene and Microbiology at the University of Würzburg studying fungal biology and comparitive genomics of Aspergillus and Candida spp, with a special focus on antifungal resistance.
Prior to that, I was a PhD student at the University of Utah in the group of Matthew Mulvey studying how the vast genetic diversity seen in Escherichia coli strains translates to differences in disease progression and host response during sepsis using a novel zebrafish model of disease we developed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vitae</title>
      <link>/top/vitae/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/top/vitae/</guid>
      <description>Curriculum Vitae last updated: November 1, 2019
A pdf version of my complete CV can be found here
Details
Education
Positions
Research Support and Awards
Publications
Academic Teaching Experience
Scientific Outreach
Spoken Languages
Details Amelia E. Barber
Email: amelia.barber[at]gmail.com
Citizenship: USA
Permenant Residency: Germany
 Education PhD, University of Utah (2016)
Microbiology and Immunology
+ “Zebrafish reveal variable effects of Escherichia coli during sepsis”
+ Advisor: Matthew Mulvey
BS, University of Wisconin-Madison (2006)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>