<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Amelia E. Barber </title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Amelia E. Barber </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Phylogeny vs. popularity in the birds of New Zealand</title>
      <link>/2019/11/24/nz-bird-phylogeny-popularity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/11/24/nz-bird-phylogeny-popularity/</guid>
      <description>What is the relationship between bird phylogeny and popularity? The Tidy Tuesday dataset this week is on New Zealand&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Bird of the Year 2019&amp;rdquo; so I thought it might be fun to look at how the phylogeny of the birds of NZ correlates with their popularity. Are the most popular birds closely related to each other? Or are popular birds scattered throughout the phylogenetic tree of birds in the competition?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidy Tuesday: Simpsons Guest Stars</title>
      <link>/2019/08/30/tidy-tuesday-simpsons-guest-stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/08/30/tidy-tuesday-simpsons-guest-stars/</guid>
      <description>Tidy Tuesday time, y’all It’s been months since I did a Tidy Tuesday, so I set aside an hour and said I had to post SOMETHING at the end of it. This week’s dataset was on Simpsons guest stars over the 30 (!!!) years the show has been on the air. Though I was initially tempted to do something looking at the most “famous” guest stars that have been on the show or the connectivity of the cast and guest stars in other projects outside of the show, both of those require additional data and more time than I had, so I went with the next thing that popped into my head, which was simply mapping the most common guest stars and their number of apperances in each season.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data sciencing women&#39;s cycling, pt 2</title>
      <link>/2019/08/25/data-sciencing-womens-cycling-pt-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/08/25/data-sciencing-womens-cycling-pt-2/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr The number of seasons a rider has been professional is a much better predictor of UCI ranking than age in female professional cycling and the 6th season as a professional is when the most riders have their best ranking.
In part 1 of my data sciencing of women’s professional cycling, I focused on the demographics of the women’s peloton (how the number of riders has changed over time, where the riders are from, how many seasons they stay).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data sciencing women&#39;s cycling, pt 1</title>
      <link>/2019/08/04/data-sciencing-womens-cycling-pt-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/08/04/data-sciencing-womens-cycling-pt-1/</guid>
      <description>(Title image featuring the one and only Marianne Vos from the 2019 Giro Rosa. ® Getty Images)
I am passionate about women’s cycling, so I thought what better way to christen this blog with a post combining my love of women’s cycling and data science. Women’s cycling is every bit as competitive and entertaining as men’s cycling, yet these athletes continue to struggle for equality and recognition in a male-dominated sport.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/top/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/top/about/</guid>
      <description>About Me I am currently a postdoc at the Leibniz Institute of Natural Product Research and Infection Biology - Hans Knöll Institute in Jena, Germany and the Institute for Hygiene and Microbiology at the University of Würzburg studying fungal biology and comparitive genomics of Aspergillus and Candida spp, with a special focus on antifungal resistance.
Prior to that, I was a PhD student at the University of Utah in the group of Matthew Mulvey studying how the vast genetic diversity seen in Escherichia coli strains translates to differences in disease progression and host response during sepsis using a novel zebrafish model of disease we developed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/2019/07/20/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/07/20/about-me/</guid>
      <description>I am currently a postdoc at the Leibniz Institute of Natural Product Research and Infection Biology - Hans Knöll Institute in Jena, Germany and the Institute for Hygiene and Microbiology at the University of Würzburg studying fungal biology and comparitive genomics of Aspergillus and Candida spp, with a special focus on antifungal resistance.
Prior to that, I was a PhD student at the University of Utah in the group of Matthew Mulvey studying how the vast genetic diversity seen in Escherichia coli strains translates to differences in disease progression and host response during sepsis using a novel zebrafish model of disease we developed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>/2019/07/20/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/07/20/hello-world/</guid>
      <description> Hello world (wide web)! Welcome to my personal website created in R using the blogdown package by Yihui Xie, Amber Thomas, and Alison Presmanes Hill. Additional thanks to Huabing Zhao for the “Clean White” theme and Cedric Scherer for the inspiration and helpful github repo :)
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vitae</title>
      <link>/top/vitae/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/top/vitae/</guid>
      <description>Curriculum Vitae last updated: November 1, 2019
A pdf version of my complete CV can be found here
Details
Education
Positions
Research Support and Awards
Publications
Academic Teaching Experience
Scientific Outreach
Spoken Languages
Details Amelia E. Barber
Email: amelia.barber[at]gmail.com
Citizenship: USA
Permenant Residency: Germany
 Education PhD, University of Utah (2016)
Microbiology and Immunology
+ “Zebrafish reveal variable effects of Escherichia coli during sepsis”
+ Advisor: Matthew Mulvey
BS, University of Wisconin-Madison (2006)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/search/placeholder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/search/placeholder/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>